ANDREW RICHARDSON Staff Software Engineer

+1(615) 424-6893 \diamond and yandy 698@gmail.com \diamond linked in. com/in/and rew-roland-richards on

OBJECTIVE

Staff Software Engineer with 5 years of full-stack development experience, specializing in React, JavaScript, TypeScript, and NodeJS. Proven leadership abilities demonstrated by leading a team of four engineers at Asurion and reducing build time by 50%. Seeking a challenging role to leverage my technical skills and leadership experience.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science, University of Alabama in Huntsville

2016 - 2019

Minor in Math

SKILLS

Programming Languages Libraries & Frameworks JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML/CSS

Build & Deployment Tools

ReactJS, NodeJS, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, GraphQL

Webpack, Nx, Yarn Workspaces, Git, GitHub Actions, AWS, Contentful

EXPERIENCE

Staff Software Engineer

 ${\rm Jan}~2023$ - ${\rm Present}$

Asurion

Remote

- Led a team of four engineers in the Digital Gateway space, responsible for managing enterprise websites, collectively receiving over 2 million monthly visitors.
- Engineered a templatized ingest process using Contentful, React, and GraphQL that generated over 5000 new marketing pages, resulting in a significant boost to SEO scores and a substantial increase in customer traffic.
- Mitigated security risks for Digital Gateway by eliminating 500+ vulnerabilities in one quarter.
- Optimized the CI/CD process using GitHub Actions, Node.js, and Webpack, reducing build times by 50% and increasing deployment frequency from weekly to more than 8 deployments daily.

Software Engineer

Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

Tanium

Remote

- Led a team of four engineers to create interactive exportable reports based on client dashboards using Typescript, React, Node.js, Webpack, and Go.
- Created interactive standalone HTML documents using Webpack and Node to attach the bundle to the document directly.

Frontend Software Engineer

Jun 2021 - Feb 2022

Postscript

Asurion

Remote

- Led a redesign of a React, TypeScript, and AWS web application from design to execution in 3 months.
- Contributed heavily to a React & Storybook component library to reduce development time in the web application.

Software Engineer

Jan 2020 - Jun 2021

Nashville, TN

• Created a Wi-Fi diagnostic service using M-Lab built with Typescript, React, NextJS and AWS.

- Added full automated CI/CD and using GitHub actions to reduce developer admin time by 30%.
- Merged code into a Lerna/Yarn monorepo to reduce code duplication by 40%.

SDE Intern

Amazon

May 2019 - Aug 2019

Austin, TX

- Built an internal tool to automate mobile homepage card submissions using Ruby on Rails, React, and AWS.
- Improved the concept-to-launch time of new cards by 40%.

PROJECTS

Personal Portfolio. A personal portfolio website showcasing my full-stack development skills and projects, implemented with advanced features such as dynamic content rendering and responsive design. The website was developed with React, TypeScript, Contentful, and AWS. (See it here)